No one stays at the top forever.
Casino is a crime, drama film directed by Martin Scorsese.
In Las Vegas, two best friends--a casino executive and a Mafia enforcer--compete
for a gambling empire and a fast-living, fast-loving socialite.
Sam "Ace" Rothstein, played by Robert De Niro.
Ginger McKenna, played by Sharon Stone.
Nicky Santoro, played by Joe Pesci.
Lester Diamond, played by James Woods.
Billy Sherbert, played by Don Rickles.
Andy Stone, played by Alan King.
Casino is a 1995 epic crime film directed by Martin Scorsese, adapted by Scorsese and Nicholas
Pileggi from the latter's nonfiction book Casino: Love and Honor in Las Vegas.
It stars Robert De Niro, Sharon Stone, Joe Pesci, Don Rickles,
Kevin Pollak, Frank Vincent and James Woods.
The film was the eighth collaboration between director Scorsese and De Niro.
Casino follows Sam "Ace" Rothstein (De Niro), a Jewish-American gambling expert handicapper who is asked by the
Chicago Outfit to oversee the day-to-day casino and hotel operations at the Tangiers Casino in Las Vegas.
Other significant characters include Nicky Santoro (Pesci), a "made man" and childhood friend of Ace, and Ginger
McKenna (Stone), a streetwise chip hustler whom Ace marries, and with whom he has a daughter.
The film details Ace's operation of the casino, the difficulties he confronts in his job, the Mafia's involvement with the
casino, and the gradual breakdown of his relationships and standing, as Las Vegas changes over the years.
The primary characters are based on real people: Ace is inspired by the life of Frank Rosenthal, also known as "Lefty", who ran
the Stardust, Fremont, Marina, and Hacienda casinos in Las Vegas for the Chicago Outfit from 1968 until 1981.
Nicky and Ginger are based on mob enforcer Anthony Spilotro and
former dancer and socialite Geri McGee, respectively.
Casino was released on November 22, 1995, by Universal Pictures, to a mostly
positive critical reception, and was a worldwide box office success.
Stone's performance was singled out for acclaim, earning her a Golden Globe Award for Best Actress
in a Motion Picture – Drama and a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of drug abuse, casino, based on
novel or book, poker, italian american.
The tone is dark and emotional.